Now, let's go and discuss the second capability of Amazon SageMaker called us SageMaker feature store.
So, before we discuss SageMaker feature store, let's take a quick look at what are features.
Now, let's say we have a dataset where we are trying to predict whether the
annual income of a individual is less than or more than $50,000 US dollars and we have all these
attributes. So, we have the age, work class, final weight, education and so on. So, all of these
are called as features which help in predicting whether the income would be more or less than $50,000.
So, these are all features. So, with this knowledge, let's try and understand SageMaker feature store.
Now, features store maps to the feature engineering phase within data processing.
So, why do we need SageMaker feature store? Let's take an example of a insurance company where
there are different teams working on different machine learning models. So, we have one team that's
working on calculating the vehicle total loss and another team that's working on customer churn.
Now, both these teams require data from similar data sources. Let's say,
vehicle damage, images, claims whether customers, text interaction with the call center,
telemetry data. Now, we might have some variation in the features that both of these teams are
using, but the data sources are pretty similar. So, one way to do it is that both of these teams
go ahead and extract this data, clean this data, transform this data, and then use it.
The other way is that single team extracts all this data, cleanses this data, transform this data,
and then stores it in something like SageMaker feature store. And then each of these teams can
search this feature store and use the training data stored within SageMaker feature store.
So, now, how does the SageMaker feature store work? So, you could have two kind of data sources.
So, you could have streaming data sources through Amazon Kinesis,
data stream, or you could have batch data sources from Amazon S3, Redshift, and so on.
So, once we ingest the data, then we create a feature catalog, which can be searched and reused
by different teams within the organization. So, you could either use it for real-time feature
look of for inferencing, or you could also use it as an offline feature to train the models.
Now, if we take a look at the formal definition of Amazon SageMaker feature store,
so it's a fully managed purpose built repository to store, share, and manage features for machine
learning models. Now, let's take a look at some of the capabilities of SageMaker feature store.
So, the first one is, it can ingest data and do feature processing. So, we already saw that
you can ingest the data either through streaming or batch data sources. And you could have streaming
data like click stream, sensor data, application as service logs, or batch, such as S3, Redshift,
data lake, and so on. So, once you ingest the data, then you can store the features,
catalog them, search, and reuse. So, SageMaker feature store will tag and index the
feature group so that they are easily discoverable. So, here you have a screenshot from the feature
store. So, we have the feature catalog and feature group catalog. And here we have feature catalog,
so feature name has gets customer ID, age. So, these are the different features that we have stored
within the feature store. Now, what you can do is, you can group these features together.
So, you have grouped all the similar features within a particular group. And you can see the feature
group name here. And it can be either online or offline. So, online you would use for
inferencing and offline, you will use for training the model. So, now you have ingested the data,
stored the data. So, now the third capability it offers is that it can be both online and offline
features. So, online features we already discussed are for real-time prediction and offline features
are for model training. Now, for offline features, it uses by default AWS Glue data catalog that
is automatically created. And once you have this data catalog, you can use Amazon Athena to carry
the features. So, you can see here, we have data catalog, offline store and AWS data catalog is
automatically created for your offline feature store. And you can write and execute SQL queries
using Amazon Athena on an AWS Glue data catalog. So, AWS data catalog allows us to search
for features based on metadata. Okay, that is pretty much it from this lecture. I hope
at a high level it is clear to you the capabilities of the SageMaker feature store.